(crickets chirping)
(woman panting)
(gasping)
(panting continues)
(panting, whimpering)
(pastor):
I was sent to a land,
a wild land...
starved for God's guidance.
But then, I arrived here
in St. Belvedere.
I swear I heard God whisper,
"This is your place
to do my work."
And all the doubt,
all temptations vanished,
because I had found it.
Your true path is what saves you
from a life of uncertainty.
We have new faces here today.
The family of Julian Grimm.
He lived here as a boy.
Does anyone recognize him?
When the mines shut, his family
left, out into that sprawl.
He forgot our ways,
and out there,
he struggled.
But he found prayer again.
And you know, prayer brought him
back here.
Town of his youth.
That was the Creator saying,
"This is your path."
Here, we have a divine energy.
(woman laughing)
So, let us bring Julian
and his blossoming family
back into the fold.
- Welcome, Julian...
- (woman): Welcome home.
- (pastor): and your family.
- (Julian): Thank you, Pastor.
- I appreciate that.
- (man): Welcome.
(man 2):
Welcome to the community.
(laughing,
indistinct chattering)
(woman 2):
I know.
(woman 3):
How old is your daughter?
(indistinct chattering)
Let's go find your mom, yeah?
Hey.
- Tiny. Tiny bites.
- Em?
Honey, this is Babette Peters.
She goes to your new school.
Maybe you two can be friends.
(church bell tolling)
(Mrs. Peters): Uh,
if you'd like, we could plan
a proper introduction.
(Babette):
She's a bad seed.
It's because she hasn't got
a proper paternal figure.
(newscaster): concerns there
will be flooding in the region.
The concerns raised are valid,
as flooding
would have an effect
on crop rotation...
(sighing)
(Julian): How you feeling?
You okay back there?
Honey, I'm fine.
(Julian):
Okay, okay.
I just worry.
That's all.
(Anna): I know.
(newscaster): The search is on
for inmate James Gillespie...
What are you readin' here, kid?
It's a comic book.
Aren't you a little old
for these?
(Anna):
Hon, that's a check stop ahead.
- I like them.
- "I like them."
(newscaster):
Gillespie is still at large...
- (Julian): Oh, come on.
- and is wanted for
aggravated assault
and attempted murder.
(Julian): Officer?
(officer): Licence and
registration, please.
That's my vehicle registration.
(officer):
Mr. Grimm. Julian.
Thank you.
- You Julian Grimm?
- Yep.
Dude, it's Teddy!
- Theodore Short.
- Oh. Teddy.
We were kids together.
We were in the same class!
I didn't even recognize you.
Oh, this old thing?
Come on, man.
- No, no. You look good.
- I tell... You know what?
It's right that you're back.
Back to your roots.
Home.
And you know, I don't want
to inconvenience you, but, uh,
I got to inspect your vehicle.
I gotta take a look in the back, see?
Teddy, we're just
on the way home.
My wife, she's with child.
There's nothing I...
Oh. Congratulations.
There's nothing I'd like better
than to get you on your way.
It's just we got
a report of a teen...
hasn't been seen in a few days.
So, it's just protocol.
We'll make it quick.
- Yep.
- (Teddy): Do what we gotta do.
I suspect it's just, like,
a runaway kind of situation.
You know, we're not
super concerned as a...
(sighing)
Are you feeling okay, Mom?
(scoffing)
You and your dad.
Such worrywarts.
Try to get along, okay?
Okay.
(Julian and Teddy chattering
indistinctly)
(classical music playing
through headphones)
(♪)
(Teddy): Uh...
we could reminisce all day.
(Julian): Good seeing you.
We'll catch up.
(Teddy): All right. We will...
Yes. We will catch up.
- We will catch up.
- (car door opening)
(Teddy): Are you so happy to be
in your daddy's hometown?
(Julian): Emerson,
he asked you a question.
(Teddy): You know,
you wanna get on your way,
and that's what you should do.
- We will catch up soon.
- (Julian): Thanks, Teddy.
- (Teddy): All right, my friend.
- Good seeing you, buddy.
(Teddy):
I can't believe it. Man!
(ignition turning)
(Julian): Couldn't answer
a simple question, no?
Can't make that effort?
Julian.
(Julian):
Just daydreaming...
Emerson world.
One day, you're just
gonna wander off,
just wander off in la-la land. And then,
the police are gonna have to look for you,
like that teen
he was talking about.
Be a part of the family.
Help us out here.
(tires squealing)
- (Julian): God damn it!
- (Emerson): I saw something!
God damn it, Emerson! What the hell were you
thinking, grabbing the wheel like that?!
- (Anna): Julian!
- She almost crashed the car!
- I saw something!
- Get out!
- I don't know the way home!
- I don't care if you don't know
- the way home! Get out now!
- (Anna): Stop it!
(whimpering)
(engine starting)
(crying)
(sniffling, whimpering)
(engine revving)
(panting)
(whimpering)
- (screaming)
- (Julian): Emerson?
Dad!
(Julian): Emerson?
Emerson, I'm here!
- Emerson?
- Dad!
Emerson, come here!
Come here. Come here.
Emerson, hey, hey, hey.
I got you. It's okay.
No. No. We have to go.
Didn't you see it?
We have to go.
- Don't you see it?
- There's nothing there.
I don't. Look, Emerson.
There's nothing there.
- Em.
- No. No, Daddy.
You didn't see it.
We have to go.
Emerson, there's nothing there.
Maybe you saw a shadow,
or maybe you saw
a big old grouchy bear, or...
maybe I just scared you.
Right?
- I don't wanna be here.
- I know.
I hate it here.
I need you to, um...
I need you be on my team
for a little while, okay?
Just help with Mom
just for a little bit
until the baby's born.
I'm sorry.
(birds chirping)
- (door opening)
- Mom!
(Anna):
I'm not looking.
(Emerson):
Knock, please.
(Anna): Okay. I'm sorry.
Here you go.
(kids chattering)
- What's this?
- I...
Can I see?
Yeah, sure.
(scoffing)
What? Are you, like, 10?
- 15.
- Hmm.
(school bell ringing)
(thudding locker)
(teacher):
Any questions for our new girl?
Come on.
(Joshua):
Yeah, actually.
- Why do you got a boy's name?
- (students laughing)
- (teacher): Oh, there we go.
- It's unisex.
- (laughing)
- (teacher): Joshua!
Maybe one of you could say
hello, hi.
Emerson, why don't you borrow
Rebecca's desk for today?
(Delilah):
Hey, but that...
(teacher): Miss Grimm
has to sit somewhere.
We'll get her a new desk
when Rebecca returns.
All right.
Who's completed the reading
for today?
Freedom of speech.
Can someone please
give me some help here?
Come on.
Someone must have read it.
Delilah?
A very pretty colour,
but not for school.
- (Joshua): Ooh!
- Shh! That's enough.
Come on, Delilah.
Let's have it.
(in faux French accent):
Come on, Delilah.
(teacher): Stop it. Simon, stop.
That's enough, now.
Stop. Stop it.
- (students laughing)
- Now!
Okay. Who can help out
our Delilah? Anyone?
Joshua? Good.
(Joshua): In the play, the
teacher, Mr. Cates, tells his...
(laughing)
- (Delilah): Hi.
- (Rachel): Love the makeup.
(girls chattering)
What the fuck are you doing?
You hiding?
(Emerson): No.
Not exactly.
It's okay if you are.
(lighter clicking)
So, um... you moved to that
house past the tracks, right?
Yeah.
We're neighbours, then.
(Emerson): Cool.
(Delilah): Saw you at
the church. You into that stuff?
(coughing)
Uh, no.
My mad believes that the godly
powers of St. Belvedere
will somehow help my mother
carry a baby full term.
But she looked knocked up.
(Emerson): Yeah.
Yeah. It's the longest that
she's managed since she had me.
Do you have something to eat?
Yeah.
Here.
Um, the lady that you were with?
(Delilah): Gracie.
She's my mom.
She was very pretty.
No.
Uh, it's nothing.
Really, I...
(classical music playing
through headphones)
(giggling)
(whispering):
We could escape.
What?
We could escape if you wanna.
Divine energy!
(both giggling)
(♪)
- That road?
- Yeah?
It takes you out of here,
to freedom.
One day, I'm going to hitch
a ride and make my escape.
(car horn honking)
(engine revving)
- Bonjour.
- (gasping)
(laughing nervously)
Hey, Frank.
- You got a smoke for me?
- Sure thing.
Huh.
Thanks.
Stay out of trouble, you two.
Let's go.
(engine revving)
(tires squealing)
(Emerson):
Uh, did you know that girl?
Rebecca?
Yeah, I know her.
(Emerson):
Wonder if she's all right.
(Delilah): So, this acrobat?
Tons of makeup.
And the host,
he kept saying she had talent,
but he was a total perv.
If I was in the talent show,
I'd sing.
Maybe I'll sing for you
sometime.
Hey!
What's up?
I was here in the woods
yesterday.
(Delilah):
So, what's the big deal?
This... This thing,
it came after me, and...
What thing?
(Emerson): I don't know.
I think I saw a monster.
What did it look like?
Well, I only saw it
for a second,
but it was enormous.
And it looked like
it was made out of the trees,
but also like a man,
'cause it had this face.
That's not important, though.
It was...
It was how it made me feel.
Like... Like if it got me,
I would just disappear.
(whispering): I have protection,
and it's really sharp.
(switchblade clicking)
This is what
I wanted to show you.
Come out!
Come out and meet Emerson!
(Emerson):
Please don't.
(Delilah):
My other person lives in here.
The secret one everybody
tells you not to be.
You're like the...
the Scythians, with the whole
"other person" thing.
Yeah. Maybe.
It's just something
Pastor Carl says.
Like, evil spirits
that follow us around.
They jump in our body,
and if we lose the good path,
make us sin.
Not these.
These were more for protection.
Like, uh...
Like, we've all got
this really dark spirit
hidden inside of us,
and well, if you summon it,
you unleash its power
to make you fearless.
For battle, or...
well, anything, really.
You had to be careful, though,
not to let it out for too long,
because, well, the spirit,
it lived for blood.
Anyway, um, the Scythians,
when they were done
with their dark spirits,
they would find a cave,
and they'd bury them there
for safekeeping.
(female DJ):
Welcome back to 98.9 FM,
where the hits keep on rolling.
And now, I'd like to play
for you a tune
that will get you dancing
in your car seats.
(Delilah):
Oh yeah.
♪ Black and white
dancing together ♪
- Wait.
- Okay.
♪ Side by side
we'll make things better ♪
♪ You're never alone
dancing together ♪
Perfect.
♪ Side by side
through stormy weather ♪
Gracie says I was born dancing.
(Emerson): Really?
♪ You're never alone,
never alone, never alone ♪
Yeah.
She was not lying.
Oh, no.
I don't really dance.
♪ Never alone, never alone ♪
♪ Never alone,
never alone ♪
You got it!
♪ You're never alone ♪
- And turn.
- Oh!
Em?
Em, where were you?
You were supposed to be home.
No, it's okay.
I made a friend.
(Anna): Honey, your daddy's been
looking for you everywhere.
(gunshot)
It's okay.
It was just a rabbit.
- I know.
- Okay.
♪ Black and white
dancing together ♪
(tuning radio to static)
Where were you?
Delilah was just showing me
around town.
I thought it'd be all right.
(Anna): See?
Everything's fine.
(Julian): Delilah?
I'm gonna kindly have
to ask you to go home.
(radio playing music and static)
Can someone please
turn that down?
- Ah.
- (changing radio station)
(newscaster): Authorities
in the area stated
the remains of
a 15-year-old girl,
Rebecca Day, from
the St. Belvedere community,
have been found.
(static)
Based on their findings,
the death is being determined
as the result of
a wild animal attack.
However, district authorities
are still required
to rule out foul play.
It is being requested
that residents of the area
take necessary precautions
until further information
is available.
(teacher):
What's important specifically
for all you young ladies
and for you little ones,
is that you be extra cautious
when going outside.
That's right.
Anyone physically vulnerable
should try and be with
a proper guardian,
especially in the night.
- Tommy?
- Do they know what it was yet?
There has been talk
of a mountain lion.
- (gasping)
- A mountain lion?
(Pastor Carl): That is
something we can contain.
(Delilah):
How?
Those of you with
fathers will know,
the men have come together
and volunteered to patrol
the town's perimeters,
to hunt down within our borders
any animals deemed
a potential threat.
I'd like to volunteer
for the hunt.
(Pastor Carl): Well, as long
as you're with your father...
It wasn't an animal.
It was a monster.
Emerson, she saw it.
(whispering):
Tell them.
No, no. It's fine.
(Pastor Carl): Stand up, please.
You can tell us what you saw.
- I... don't exactly know.
- (girls whispering)
- A monster.
- (Pastor Carl): Yeah.
Can you describe its appearance?
I was in the woods,
and at first, it chased me.
But then, it was in the trees...
And you're sure
it chased you, darling?
- (girl whispering)
- I think. I...
I think you should talk
about this to them privately.
Come on!
Let us drop
this monster nonsense.
This is no time for gossip,
for stories.
Freak.
(Pastor Carl):
This is a time to remain calm.
Hey!
(mockingly):
"I saw a monster."
(girl): Someone died.
It's not a joke.
- Um, Emerson?
- (Billie-Jean): Abby!
(Abby): I wanted to talk...
- (Billie-Jean): Seriously?
- Yeah.
God, Pastor Carl
is such a dickwad.
- Let's get out of here.
- I would, but I can't.
Sure you can.
Come on.
That was confidential
information.
What?
Now they all think
I'm a lunatic.
Who cares?
You had to tell.
(♪)
(newscaster):
Wednesday, periods of rain.
A high of 12 degrees.
Rain on Thursday, a high of 11.
And rain on Friday, with
a high of just 8 degrees.
In Lethbridge tonight, cloudy...
Hey, girls. Minors can't smoke
in here, honey.
(newscaster): Chance of showers
or a thunderstorm, a low of 7.
(server): Sorry about your
friend. It's just terrible.
I gotta ask.
Is it smart for the two of you
to be out on your own
like this right now?
Coffee and a burger.
Extra big and bloody.
Thanks.
Uh, just a water is good for me.
You bet.
(Delilah):
I think we should do it.
Release our dark spirits.
Delilah, that was...
That was just a story.
What?
It's just...
I... I read it in this.
This is for kids.
Yeah, but... but it's based on
anthropological stuff.
It's true, in a way.
It's, like, about people
from a long, long time ago.
And, uh, what they did,
it's real.
They really did it.
So then, we can do it, too.
Yeah, but...
Get the things we need
and we do it tonight.
Tonight? No, no.
Delilah, my dad...
- Come on! Sneak out.
- He would kill us.
- My dad would kill me, Delilah.
- (sighing)
Do you like it?
Being scared all the time?
Why not be more?
Like, see if you could
try to change that.
Don't you want to change that?
(clicking)
(bottles clinking)
(Delilah whispering):
Psst. Emerson.
Hurry up.
(Emerson): You can do this.
You can do this. It's fine.
Oh, wait. Wait.
(crickets chirping)
Yeah. I think this could be
a good spot.
(Delilah):
Okay.
(Emerson): Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. That's good.
Okay.
(Delilah):
So, how do we do this, then?
(Emerson): Uh, mainly,
I think we have to release it
from our bodies.
From our...
From our blood.
So, I brought...
I brought this for a pinprick.
Even better.
Sugar.
I've... We have
to make a circle.
Here.
To seal in our energy.
Now, we need to dig a hole,
so we can, like,
connect to the elements.
(distant screeching)
It's just coyotes.
Uh, now what?
(Emerson): I think we have
to go into a trance
by saying an incantation.
Do you know one of those?
Well, I think
I could just make it up.
Ahm-dash-ka.
(both giggling)
Ahm-mu-rush-ka.
Okay. Uh...
A-bu-re-di-ma-ka.
A-bi-dua-ka!
(both laughing)
A-ki-roo-shi-ya!
Ai-koo-ra-foo-shwa.
Koo-koo-rak-shi-ah.
Oh-kala-shaia-wa.
Ki-nu-ra!
Koo-ra-shi-ka.
Ah-ku-ra-gra!
(overlapping chanting)
Mi-ka-sha!
Mi-ka...
(panting)
(grunting)
(both panting)
(crickets chirping)
(Delilah):
Shit!
- Who the fuck is that?
- (Emerson): Is it hunters?
Run! Go!
(both panting)
(tires grinding on gravel)
(panting)
(Delilah):
Hey. Psst.
I think they're gone.
(both giggling)
(both panting, laughing)
(rustling)
(Delilah):
What was this?
I don't know.
(rustling closer)
Delilah?
Where did you go?
(Delilah): Emerson!
Do you have your flashlight?
Yeah, yeah.
(leaves crunching)
Delilah?
Delilah, run!
Run!
(panting)
(Delilah):
Emerson?
Emerson!
I found the dark spirit.
(birds chirping)
Delilah?
(Julian):
Emerson?
- (knocking on door)
- Wake up.
(Emerson whispering):
You gotta go.
(Anna):
Em?
Did you lock the door?
Are you awake?
Yeah, Mom. I'm up.
(Anna): Me or Dad will be there
to pick you up after school, okay?
Actually, uh, Mom,
Delilah's mom said
she could drive me home.
(Anna):
Have you met her?
Yeah.
Hey.
I have a question.
Do you feel strange?
I feel like I'm going
to jump out of my skin.
That thing last night, I thought
we were dead for sure.
Yeah, I know. I...
I've been thinking about it,
and maybe the two of us
just isn't enough if...
We just weren't ready yet.
But next time, our dark spirit
will make us stronger.
(Joshua):
Hey.
Oh, shit.
(Joshua): Hey.
Why'd you make up
that stuff yesterday?
- Me?
- We didn't.
Oh. She's your
replacement friend?
Hey, hey!
- Give that back!
- No. Give me a blowjob first.
Ew!
You can't say that!
- What? She's done it before.
- Give that back!
(Simon):
Don't touch that fucking bag.
(teacher):
What are you doing down there?!
Oh, shit.
(laughing)
Come on!
(teacher):
I saw that, Miss Soleil!
Let's go!
Let's get to class.
Come on, girls.
Let's go.
Um, about what Simon said...
He says a lot of dumb stuff.
You're my friend
no matter what, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, of course.
(Delilah): Go away!
(Rachel): Abby,
she saw the thing
you were talking about
at assembly.
- Bullshit.
- Wait. What?
(Abby): That thing you saw
in the woods?
(Delilah):
Oh, yeah?
So, why didn't you say anything
before, at assembly?
(stammering):
Because it sounds crazy.
I mean, no one believed her.
(whispering):
Maybe they should do it.
(Rachel): We were thinking if,
like, we went to Pastor Carl,
but, like, together this time...
You'd probably have to die
before he'd take you seriously.
It would be better
if there were more of us.
Not them.
- Just in case.
- They'll ruin it.
(Rachel): Ruin what?
(Delilah):
When did you see it?
(Rachel):
Oh, just Abby did.
But Abby always tells the truth,
so it got me thinking
about what they said
when they found Rebecca's body,
how it was so torn up
that it was, like,
beyond recognizable.
And there were cougar tracks
around her body,
but that doesn't make sense,
because I think it was...
(Delilah):
It wasn't a fucking cougar.
(Rachel):
Yeah. That's what I'm saying.
Obviously, it was a monster.
Oh, shit.
(Delilah):
What the fuck?
Ugh.
(Rachel):
What did this?
Maybe it's hunters,
looking for pieces of her.
Rebecca.
Ugh.
(Delilah):
Emerson!
- (Rachel): Like, bleed into it?
- (Emerson): Yes. Bleed into it.
You might have to squeeze
a little bit.
Okay, okay. That's good.
I got some on me.
Yeah. You're good.
- Now what?
- Taste.
It's in the blood.
Oh.
(spitting out)
(Rachel):
Oh, my God. This is so stupid.
This is... This is
some sort of devil worship.
Explain to them
what the spirit is.
Uh, yeah, okay.
Well, it's like you called out
this part of you.
It's innate, so it's always been
in you, but hidden.
- Yeah, okay.
- Listen.
She knows stuff.
Okay. Sorry.
Now, it's free,
to make you brave, strong
for the monster.
So, if it comes,
you won't have to hide.
You can fight.
No. I don't want to go anywhere
near that thing.
Isn't, like, this
meant for protection?
- Yeah.
- Fighting is protection.
Duh.
(Rachel):
Okay.
Well, how do we start feeling
this brave or whatever?
Face me.
Oh, okay.
Do you want to feel it?
Um... yeah. Sure.
Ow! Stop!
Fuck!
What the hell?
Now, you do me.
(panting)
Now, you two try.
(Julian):
Mmm. It's good.
Mm-hmm. Mmm.
We saw some bear tracks today.
What would you do
if you met a bear?
Kill it with my "bear" hands.
(chuckling)
(laughing)
There's actually a lot
you can do with a bear.
Problem is, with a cougar,
it's a little trickier,
because they like to sneak up
behind you and pounce.
It's true.
That's why I always carry
a knife when I'm hunting.
And, uh, how...
how do you use it on them?
Stab it right in the throat.
It's suppertime.
- You want to know, right?
- Yeah.
I'm teaching her
survival skills.
Where?
Where on the neck?
You want to get that blade
as deep at it can go.
Cause a lot of pain,
maybe even kill it right there.
I sure hope
you don't have worms.
- Emerson?
- (Julian): Hey.
I hate those rabbits.
A few won't hurt.
They're going to eat
the whole garden.
I should get my gun.
No. Please just sit down, honey.
Eat your supper.
They're so sweet wittle
bunny wabbits
eating all of your cawwots,
and all of your wettuce,
and all of your woast beef?
(babbling)
All of it. All of it.
It's a vewy, vewy,
vewy frisky wabbit.
And look.
It's a vewy annoying wabbit.
- It's a very annoying wabbit.
- Dad, stop. Hush.
- Some wabbit fangs...
- (Anna laughs)
and tickling and tickling,
and then,
a little... Ow!
Weally?
It was a sneak attack
on the wabbit.
But now, the wabbit
is prepared for battle.
But first, he must get
to high ground and hop, and...
Whoa!
Oh, my goodness.
We're breaking the house, Mom!
- We're breaking the house.
- Come and sit down, please.
I'm not gonna sit down,
because there's a big,
terrifying...
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
The bear is chasing,
chasing, chasing.
- Wabbit or bear?
- Both.
Come on, kiddo.
Oh, nice.
Oh, okay. Here we go.
Oh, look at this.
Is that it?
(chuckling)
Come on, kid. You got
better than that, right?
Let's see how strong you are.
Go.
Go, kid, go.
You're like a little wab...
(screaming in pain)
Ow!
(Anna): Wha...
What happened?
(panting)
(Pastor Carl):
We have got to trust
that our Creator
has given us mankind,
the privilege, the ability,
to step out and command nature.
That means this mountain lion.
(voices chattering)
So, let us trust in our good men
to slay that beast.
It's in your spirit, your flesh.
Build the prayer up.
(overlapping prayers)
- Protect us...
- Jesus...
(Pastor Carl): Now, send it
to the Day family.
(praying continues)
(whispering):
I saw a monster. I saw it.
- (man): Protect us from evil...
- (praying continues)
You may open your eyes.
(knocking on door)
Delilah?
Guess what.
- Baby, she saw it. She...
- (Gracie speaks French)
(in French): Who is it?
(in English):
It's no one, Gracie!
Look. I just came from church.
Baby saw it.
- The monster.
- For real?
(Gracie): I can hear you talking
to somebody. Is it Frank?
- Uh, is she okay?
- (Gracie): Delilah!
Yes, yes, yes.
But Baby?
Baby, you know, I'm, like...
She's a total try hard.
(Emerson): Well, yeah.
You believe her?
Yeah. I mean,
she was genuinely scared.
But you didn't see her.
She was terrified.
But Baby?
Just think we should ask her...
to join.
She's so tight,
she probably scrubs her vagina
with bleach or something.
(in French):
Delilah, I'm sorry...
Honey!
(in English):
I didn't mean what I said, okay?
Delilah!
(crying)
Delilah?
(Gracie):
Baby!
I didn't mean what I said!
Come back!
(Emerson): Hey!
Delilah?
Hey.
(birds chirping)
Let's leave this fucking town.
Let's just go.
Everywhere.
I can sing for money,
and you're smart.
There's a lot of stuff
you could do.
Okay?
- Will you come with?
- Yeah.
Yes.
(Delilah): Oui!
(giggling)
Ow! Ow.
(Rachel):
Do me. Do it.
Pinch, pinch.
Go on. Go.
Come on. See?
I don't even feel anything.
(Abby):
Try at the centre.
(Rachel):
Try it, or I pinch you.
One or the other.
Let's go.
You got it. Come on.
Really do it.
It'll be fun.
(Abby):
Try at the centre.
(Rachel): See?
Not a big deal.
Delilah?
Delilah, come here.
Come here. Come.
It's like telepathy.
We can use these.
- That's so cool.
- I know.
Hopefully, they work.
Hello?
- (walkie-talkies beeping)
- Hello?
(giggling)
(Baby): Put those back.
Those are my dad's.
So, when did you first see it?
The monster.
I...
At night.
But behind the house,
in the shed.
But I ran away.
What were you doing in the shed?
I... I hide stuff out there
sometimes.
And that's why I couldn't tell
my mom,
'cause then,
she'd know I sneaked food.
I'd be pretty angry
if someone told me
how to eat all the time.
But you know, the dark spirit,
it eats your anger.
Isn't that right, Emerson?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
Your anger, your fear,
your rage.
That's what makes it strong.
I'm... I'm not angry.
I'm sure you are.
Um, yeah.
Uh, Baby?
Uh, come here.
Come here. Yeah. Come.
Everyone, make a circle.
You stand in the centre.
Okay.
Now, really focus.
Find your rage and scream.
(singing operatically)
(laughing)
That's okay.
Uh, it's fine.
Uh, okay.
Uh, get her to the ground.
(overlapping chatter)
Bye-bye.
(Baby):
I... Is there...?
(Emerson):
Okay, Baby.
Now, really try and concentrate
and find your rage.
(giggling)
(Emerson panting)
Yi-ey.
Yeet-sha.
Soo-na.
Ra-ka.
Ah-sha.
Sha-ka-rai.
(overlapping chanting)
(shouting, banging on box)
(shouting and banging continue)
- (screeching)
- (shrieking)
(Baby shouting)
(guttural screaming)
(shouting)
(snarling)
(shrieking)
(crying)
(crying continues)
(panting)
(laughing)
- (trilling)
- Okay. We're getting somewhere.
- Yeah.
- Sounds like a songbird.
Ca-coo, ca-coo!
Yeah.
I like that one.
- Ca-coo, ca-coo!
- Yeah. I like.
How do you do it?
Ca-coo, ca-coo!
Three, two, one.
(all):
Ca-coo, ca-coo!
- (laughing)
- That's fun.
- Yes!
- (Abby): That's awesome.
I dig it.
No. That's awesome. Okay.
(♪)
- You ready?
- For? Oh. Okay, okay.
Oh, my God!
- Abby!
- You look badass.
(Rachel): That was... Okay.
Well, it's now my turn.
- Baby, can I have it?
- Aah!
Okay. Gimme your hand.
Gimme your hands.
- Like, I want extra...
- Okay.
Gimme yours.
Okay. Ready?
Oh, yeah.
(giggling)
- You look good.
- (snapping fingers)
Hey.
This will make you feel like
your dark spirit.
What?
Is that marijuana?
(Baby): No.
It's a cigarette.
I'm talking about the joint.
Oh...
Look at this.
Have fun.
- Okay, bye.
- Baby.
- Come on.
- Are you sure?
(bird chirping)
Ooh.
Can I try?
Yeah. Wait, wait.
How am I supposed to be
holding this?
- Like this.
- Uh, okay. No.
Like, there?
There, I got it. Yeah.
(Abby): I don't know.
Should I?
- (Rachel): Yeah.
- Okay. Me too.
(Rachel):
Just a little.
(coughing)
(laughing)
Oh, my God. That burns.
(coughing)
So, uh, where did you get it?
Frank gave it to me.
Go on.
(coughing)
(laughing)
Does it...?
You're feeling powerful?
It's wonderful.
(laughing)
You're missing something.
What does it feel like?
Like your dark spirit's
emerging.
(Emerson):
Like having a great time.
(Rachel): Like you're on top
of the world.
(Billie-Jean):
Rachel? Abby?
I saw you guys come in here.
Rachel?
(twig snapping)
Ca-coo-coo!
Stop that.
- Ca-coo-coo!
- I said, stop that.
What's that on your face?
(snarling)
What are you guys doing
hanging out with these freaks?
Come on, guys.
Let's go.
- (snarling)
- (chuckling)
Come on, guys.
Rachel?
Guys?
- Ah, fuck off!
- (hissing)
(giggling)
Shh.
- Ca-coo-ca-coo!
- (giggling)
Ca-coo!
Shh, shh.
- One, two, three. Whoa!
- (objects clattering)
(glass shattering)
(cackling)
Hii-ya!
(laughing)
(smashing)
(shouting indistinctly)
I found the fireworks!
- (fireworks popping)
- (cheering)
(laughing, cheering)
(Delilah):
Are you scared?
No.
I'm not scared of nothing.
Hit me.
Yeah. Hit me.
All right.
(Rachel):
Emerson!
(laughing)
(both laughing)
(everyone laughing)
- You're ready for that?
- Do it. Do it.
(Rachel):
Okay. Go, go, go.
- (shouting)
- (laughing)
If the monster came, like, now,
like, right this fucking second,
what would you do?
I'd kill it! I'd kill it!
I'd kill it!
- Come on, you motherfucker!
- Come on!
Yeah, yeah, motherfucker!
(all shouting)
(twigs snapping)
(everyone shouting)
(people laughing)
Ah! Delilah!
You're home!
Now, it's a party!
(Lester):
You girls should be careful
wandering around in the night, huh?
We'll protect them.
We're out hunting.
You're here drinking, Frank.
"I am here drinking, Frank"?
Well, I'm just juicing up
for the kill, baby.
(screaming)
(laughing)
- (Misty): You scared me.
- (laughing)
(Frank): Hell, we can start
the fucking party!
- You belong here.
- Beer!
(overlapping chatter)
- Delilah...
- (Lester): Hey, hey, hey!
(Frank): A toast.
To the beautiful Soleil women.
- (Delilah): And to Emerson.
- And to Emerson.
Emerson. Cheers.
- Cheers.
- Chug.
- Chug!
- Chug. Chug. Chug!
- Chug, chug, chug, chug!
(all chanting)
Woo!
(laughing)
(Frank): That's what I'm fucking
talking about.
There you go.
- (laughing)
- All right. Okay. Shh.
When I was a kid, I could fly.
- I could.
- Darling?
I just wanted to tell you
that you're family, okay?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Delilah has said nothing
but good things about you.
And I want you to know that
you can come here anytime.
- Okay, honey?
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Thank you.
(laughing)
T'es belle!
(Frank): I think I knew your
daddy when I was growing up.
You just moved back here.
Is that right?
Yes, sir.
- Sir?
- (laughing)
And it's a good thing
you did, too,
because she would've been
so lonely.
See, her and Rebecca,
you were thick as thieves, huh?
(Misty):
Oh, they were the best friends.
- (Gracie): Like sisters.
- (Misty): Yeah.
Oh, sad.
To Rebecca.
Sweet, sweet girl,
may you rest in peace.
(Misty):
To Rebecca.
- (Frank): Rest in peace.
- (Misty): It's a sad day.
Oops!
(Lester):
Oh! She's a lightweight!
(laughing)
(overlapping chatter)
- (thudding)
- Oh!
Oh, kitten.
You look like you seen
a ghost or something.
(Gracie): Come on.
Let's go. Sing for us.
- Yes.
- (Frank): Come on, pop star.
(cheering)
(Gracie): Delilah!
- (applauding)
- (karaoke music)
- (cheering)
- Delilah!
♪ All through the night ♪
♪ This precious time ♪
♪ When time is new ♪
Woo-hoo!
♪ Oh, all through the night ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ Knowing that
we feel the same ♪
♪ Without saying ♪
♪ We have no past ♪
♪ We won't reach back ♪
♪ Keep with me ♪
♪ Forward
all through the night ♪
♪ And once we start ♪
♪ The metre clicks ♪
♪ And it goes running ♪
♪ All through
the night ♪
♪ Until it ends ♪
♪ There is no end ♪
♪ All through the night ♪
♪ Stray cat is crying ♪
♪ So stray cat sings back ♪
♪ All through the night ♪
♪ They have forgotten ♪
♪ What by day they lack ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Under those
white street lamps ♪
♪ They have
a little chance ♪
♪ They may see ♪
♪ We have no past ♪
♪ We won't reach back ♪
♪ Keep with me ♪
♪ Forward
all through the night ♪
♪ And once we start ♪
♪ The metre clicks ♪
♪ And it goes running ♪
♪ All through the night ♪
Have you ever kissed anyone
before?
Of course.
Plenty of times.
How many?
Delilah, I'm tired.
I'm really glad you're here.
Everything feels possible
with you.
(heavy breathing)
(twig snapping)
(snarling)
- (Pastor Carl): Argh...
- (Teddy): Carl, Carl?
I, uh... I've been thinking
about this, and the thing is,
this could all just be
a result of frustration.
Yes. Some, um... Yeah,
we haven't caught the animal,
so some...
just some kids acting out...
(Pastor Carl):
Are you pig-ignorant?!
Whoever did this, they cannot be
from this community.
If you know something,
anything...
come forward.
For if you know
but do not speak,
you will be deemed evil.
As evil as that beast!
(Mr. Dangerfield):
He got it!
My boy!
Joshua, my boy.
Joshy got it.
He shot that big damn cat
that got that Day girl.
Joshua, he got it!
(man):
He got him! Woo-hoo!
(cheering)
You kill anything.
You do that. You do that!
Dad?
(Julian): Oh, Emerson.
(chuckling)
You just wander and wander
and wander and wander.
Want to borrow my shirt?
Are you cold?
No.
No, I'm good, Dad.
I know that you told those
stories because you were scared.
But I will protect you,
and I promise you...
this is our home.
We kill anything
that fucks with our home.
(man): Yeah!
We kill anything that fucks
with our home, gentlemen!
(cheering)
(cheering continues)
- Delilah?
- Come on.
They're waiting for us.
I think we should take
our spirits to the cave.
(chuckling)
I don't think it's good,
what we're becoming.
Don't fucking say that.
Come on.
Delilah. They got it.
(Delilah):
That cougar?
You think that's for real?
Come.
We set a trap with Baby
to catch the monster.
(Emerson): Delilah.
You and Rebecca?
You should've told me
that you were friends.
(Delilah):
She saw it.
Just like you.
Rebecca, she told me,
and I knew.
Before she disappeared,
she told me what she saw.
(Emerson): I don't want
to do this anymore.
I don't have to do everything
you say.
You're my best friend.
I saw you.
- What?
- With that guy.
Your mom's boyfriend.
(thudding)
(Delilah):
So what?
You think I'm a whore now?
Yeah? Well, you don't get it,
'cause he really likes me.
He's, like, 30,
and it's weird, Delilah.
We're just...
Shut up! Shut up!
- It's not right!
- Shut up!
You're just jealous
'cause I'm wanted,
and nobody wants
some tit-less virgin like you.
(indistinct chattering)
(distant shouting)
What?
(opening can)
Wait, um...
Shouldn't we, like, lie down?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Can you take this off?
Yeah.
(zipper rasping)
(girl shouting indistinctly)
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Wait.
(Delilah):
Baby?!
Wait. Wait.
- (girls shouting indistinctly)
- Baby?
Shh. Wait.
(Joshua):
Who's that?
(distant shouting)
(Abby):
The monster got Baby!
- (Rachel): It got Baby! Run!
- Wait, where's Delilah?
(Rachel): She's still back
there, but don't go! Run!
(panting)
Delilah!
Hey, hey.
(gasps)
You okay?
Is she alive?
We were going to kill it,
but we came too late.
This knife, it can't protect us.
I don't want this.
- I don't want this!
- Okay, okay.
(Mrs. Peters):
Teddy? Teddy, Teddy, Teddy.
- Teddy!
- (Mr. Peters): Denise!
(Mrs. Peters):
Teddy, who is it? Babette.
(screaming):
No, no, no!
What is happening?!
Oh, my God!
What did you do?
What did you do?!
My daughter!
My baby!
(Pastor Carl):
You know not to go out alone,
into the night.
You know that.
Yet you made yourselves
vulnerable
to elements out of our control.
You all sent Babette alone
into the woods.
What were you doing?
(Billie-Jean):
I seen 'em.
A few days back.
I saw them all in the woods,
calling out devils.
Abby?
We... We didn't mean to.
- It was a trap.
- Abby, don't!
(Pastor Carl): What does
that mean, "It was a trap"?
- To catch the monster.
- Shh. Shh.
- Abby!
- I'm sorry.
Monster?
We all saw it.
It wasn't just me.
(Pastor Carl):
What did you do?
I told them not to.
I said it was too much,
but you two made her.
You were there, too!
We can explain.
We were just try...
Emerson, don't tell him!
(Pastor Carl):
Tell me what?
(Abby): We, uh...
Abby, don't.
We did something
with our dark spirits.
(Pastor Carl):
Dark spirits?
(Rachel):
Abby, please stop.
(Pastor Carl):
Who started this? Rachel?
Um, no. Um...
No. Rachel!
(Rachel):
No. I, I... No, no.
It was, uh, her.
Them. They made us.
We didn't want to!
You snake!
No, that's not true.
You were scared,
and so we invited you
to do the ritual.
They're crazy!
They made us eat blood.
I said I didn't want to.
- I didn't want to, either!
- Stop lying!
- I'm not lying.
- Abby, shut up!
- It's your fault!
- (all shouting)
Calm down!
Calm down.
Was it Emerson Grimm's idea?
(people whispering)
I think it might have been.
I, uh... I don't...
It was mine.
It was my idea.
All of it.
Me and Rachel, we thought if...
if only one of us went,
we could trick it.
We didn't mean for it
to happen like it did.
(scoffing)
What I cannot understand is
what you were planning to do
when you caught this.
We were going to kill it.
With these dark spirits?
Carl, they're just kids.
It's only make-believe.
(Pastor Carl):
I know. I know that.
This power you think you have,
it is not real!
Did you think it was real, Abby?
- Yes.
- Yes?
Help me, all of you.
Please pray for these girls.
(overlapping prayers)
- (Abby): No!
- (Pastor Carl): Confess,
and you will be forgiven
for your hoax.
I will release you
from your sins.
No. No.
(thudding)
(onlookers murmuring)
(onlookers continue praying
indistinctly)
(whispering indistinctly)
Confess
and you will be forgiven.
I release you from your sins.
(thudding)
No, no!
We were just...
We just wanted to be brave!
We just...
We just wanted to be brave.
(Pastor Carl):
Yes, yes.
You have suffered, but your
innocence can be restored.
What you did was wrong,
but you must confess,
and you will be forgiven.
(thudding)
Julian.
You came to me.
You told me your daughter...
She started acting out
when she met Delilah Soleil.
(whispering)
(Pastor Carl):
Dolores,
your Rebecca and Delilah
were friends
around the time of
her disappearance?
Delilah, Delilah.
(crying)
I see now how deeply troubled
you are.
If I only had seen it sooner.
The town's council and I,
we believe it best
if we request
your immediate placement
in a facility where you can get
the care you need!
(whimpering)
Emerson! Emerson!
Where's my mom?
Where's Gracie?
Emerson! Emerson, please.
Emerson!
(crying)
- No! Don't touch me!
- Don't!
Don't touch me!
(shrieking):
Emerson! Emerson!
(crying)
Emerson, honey,
you should eat something.
- (banging)
- (gasping)
(crying)
(switch clicking)
(whispering):
Delilah?
Delilah, hey.
Are you there?
(static)
Everyone was just so loud
and angry at us.
I... I'm sorry.
I didn't know what to do.
(static)
I think we should run away.
You know, we could...
We can meet up tomorrow
and go down to that road
and hitch a ride,
like you said we could.
Just get out of
this fucking town.
(static)
I'm gonna go to the cave at dawn
to bury my dark spirit.
Could you meet me there?
I'll wait, Delilah.
Okay?
Please.
(walkie-talkie beeping)
(birds chirping)
(zipper rasping)
(twig snapping)
(distant rustling)
(panting)
(shouting)
Argh!
- (grunting)
- (shouting)
(Emerson):
No, no, no!
No, no! Stop!
(thudding)
- (shouting)
- (grunting)
No! No!
- Ah!
- (whimpering)
- (screaming)
- (shouting)
(shouting continues)
(grunting)
(screeching)
(shrieking)
(choking)
(Delilah):
Emerson.
(both shouting)
Please, Emerson.
Emerson, please, please.
Get up!
Get up. Emerson, please!
(man shouting)
(panting)
(Delilah shouting)
(whimpering)
(panting)
(man grunting)
(screaming)
(whimpering)
(shouting)
(grunting)
(man grunting)
(panting)
(birds chirping)
Hey.
♪ When I was a young boy ♪
♪ My mama said to me ♪
♪ "There's only one girl
in the world for you ♪
♪ And she probably lives
in Tahiti" ♪
♪ I'd go
the whole wide world ♪
♪ I'd go the whole wide world
just to find her ♪
♪ Or maybe she's in
the Bahamas ♪
♪ Where the Caribbean Sea
is blue ♪
♪ Weeping in
the tropical moonlit night ♪
♪ Because nobody's told her
about you ♪
♪ I'd go
the whole wide world ♪
♪ I'd go the whole wide world
just to find her ♪
I'd go the whole wide world ♪
♪ To find out where
they hide her ♪
♪ I'd go
the whole wide world ♪
♪ I'd go the whole wide world
just to find her ♪
♪ Why am I hanging around
in the rain right here ♪
♪ Trying to pick up
a girl ♪
♪ Why are my eyes filling up
with these lonely tears ♪
♪ When there's girls
all over the world ♪
♪ And is she lying on
a tropical beach somewhere ♪
♪ Underneath a tropical sun ♪
♪ Pining away
in a heatwave there ♪
♪ Hoping that
I won't be long ♪
♪ I should be lying on that
sun-soaked beach with her ♪
♪ Caressing
her warm brown skin... ♪
(♪)